Resume

TOMOYUKI KASHIRO

Front-end Engineer

Birth Date 30 / 04 / 1985

Languages Japanese(native), English(conversational)

Nationality Japan

Website http://tomoyukikashiro.me

Github https://github.com/tomoyukikashiro

Email ksrtmyk@gmail.com

Summary

I'm web developer. I work as a Front-end engineer mainly but I have experience Python and Ruby.

So I've been working web developer for 8 years.

I'm working in U.S. now.

As a Front-end engineer, I have the skills to create the standard HTML which make it easy to fix any problems that arise later. I try to use new technology to improve UI/UX or maintainability such as new library and new APIs.

As a project manager, I can suggest architecture to make what a client want to get and consider with best team. And I have excellent communication skills with the ability to interact effectively verbally and in writing I also have the ability to lead and manage a team of developers from the beginning of a project to the end.

I have also experience Back-end developer using Django, Ruby on Rails. So I can discuss architecture with them and I can consider about UI/UX and architecture in whole of web service.

I will make good collaboration in your team.

http://127.0.0.1:9000/

Experience

Apr. 2008 - 2011

Java Engineer

Rakuten, Inc.

- Developed Ecommerce recommendation and ranking system utilizing Java and Perl
- · Managed API application with memcached and hadoop
- · Fixed bugs and maintained the site
- · Managed projects with the business department

2010 - Dec. 2012

Front-end Engineer

Rakuten, Inc.

- Worked in front-end development using standards based on HTML5 and CSS3 working with jQuery/jQuery mobile
- Created Javascript coding guideline and reviewed codes
- Spearheaded adoption of new principles such as responsive design and mobile first
- · Refined and iterated page speed by using server settings, cache server and front-end tool (minified source)

Jan. 2012 - Jul. 2014

Front-end Engineer

KAYAC, Inc.

- · Managed projects with designer and backend programmer
- Developed UI/UX with client and designer via prototyping (bootstrap, paper prototype)
- Developed project goal and its tactics with client (UI/UX and Measurement)
- Developed web application and campaign sites utilizing standards based on HTML5 and CSS3 and featured libraries such as AngularJS, Sencha Touch, and BackboneJS
- · Spearheaded teaching of front-end web security within the team

Jan. 2015 -

Web Developer

Freelance

- Especially good at developing E-commerce web application.
- · Front-end Developer but developed Back-end too using Ruby on Rails.
- Currently use Ruby on Rails, AngularJS and Mongodb.

April. 2016 - (in U.S.)

Web Developer

Material World

- Develop Trade-in E-commerce site.
- Not only as a Front-end but also as a Back-end developer.
- Use python(Django) and AngularJS.

http://127.0.0.1:9000/

Skills

Development Language

HTML5	****
CSS3	****
JavaScript	****
Python	****
Ruby	****
NodeJS	*****

Framework, Library

AngularJS	****
Sencha Touch	****
Django	****
Ruby on Rails	****
Build tools (gulp webpack etc)	****

Education

Apr. 2004 - Mar. 2008

Sociology

TOYO UNIVERSITY

I majored in Sociology to pursue a career as PR. However, I realized the impact of the Internet and have started to study skills such as HTML and CSS.

http://127.0.0.1:9000/